

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with a background in customer service ensuring that customers are always fully satisfied with the product and service they receive. Possessing strong analytical problem solving skills and adaptiveness, having worked alongside teams to efficiently create and develop mobile-first applications with a pronounced user experience.

EDUCATION

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY

FULL STACK CODING BOOTCAMP Grad. July 2020 | Evanston, IL

LINKS

Portfolio:// alexbailon.net Github:// alex-bailon LinkedIn:// alex-bailon

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Node.js • Express • Javascript jQuery • HTML5 • CSS3 • Bootstrap 4 JSON • MySQL • MongoDB • Vue.js React.js • Vuex • Redux • Handlebars.js Python • C#

DEVELOPMENT

Mobile-First & Responsive Design •
Test Driven Development • Object
Oriented Programming • Fundamentals
of Web Development • Data Structure
Algorithms • Database Organization
Information Security • State
Management

EXPERIENCE

FUSION92 | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

May 2020 - Aug 2020 | Chicago, IL

- Created and developed marketing material using MJML.
- Use **Email on Acid** to test and ensure generated **HTML** is fully responsive on all operation systems and email clients.
- Worked with teams of 5-10 along with other departments to ensure projects met and exceeded clients expectations.

LIFESTREAM BLOOD BANK | Hospital Services Tech II

Nov 2018 - Dec 2019 | Rosemead, CA

• Received, processed and transported blood products. Imported blood products, returns and transfers of inventory.

BANK OF THE WEST | SERVICE BANKER

Dec 2017 - Nov 2018 | Alhambra, CA

 Processed customer transactions (deposit check/cash, make payments, wire transfers). Serviced customer accounts and provide outstanding customer service.

MACY'S INC. | FINE JEWELRY CLERICAL

Aug 2016 - Feb 2018 | Arcadia, CA

• Received and merchandise inventory, ensuring all jewelry is properly displayed and organized and documents are accurately filled. Work with the sales team to provide accurate information about products.

PROJECTS

FETCH | LIVE: FETCH-WOOF-312.HEROKUAPP.COM

July 2020 | Chicago, IL

Full-stack application that allows users to match their pets with other pets so that they may set up playdates and allow their pets to be more socially active. Used React.js, Redux, MongoDB, Mongoose, Bcrypt.js, Passport.js and Express.

HOME BODY | LIVE: HEALTH-APP-2020.HEROKUAPP.COM/ Jan 2014 – Jan 2015 | Chicago, IL

Full-stack health application that helps users keep track of daily calorie, fat, sugar, and carb intake with information organized in charts. Used MySQL, Sequelize, Handelbars.is, Bcrypt.is, Passport.is, Chart.is and Express.

FLYTE | LIVE: KYLERES.GITHUB.IO/FINANCE_APP/

Jan 2014 - Jan 2015 | Chicago, IL

Front-end finance application that lets users view stock prices and news related to that stock. Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Chart.js and Materialize.

BURGER APP | LIVE: FROZEN-RETREAT-67912.HEROKUAPP.COM/

Jan 2014 – Jan 2015 | Chicago, IL

Full-stack application that has users input their favorite burgers, stores them into an MySQL database and with a click of a button 'devours' the burger (updating the database). Used EXpress.js, node.js, ORM, MySQL, Handlebars.js and Materialize.